SUDHANSHU KULKARNI Software Developer

simplysudhanshu.github.io @ sudhanshu.kulkarni.13@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/sudhanshu-kulkarni **1** +(1) 609-721 1446

github.com/simplysudhanshu San Francisco, CA

An earnest Software Developer bringing deep research and application-oriented profile to the table. My years of experience ensure clean, efficient software, and I'm diving headfirst (coffee in hand!) into the exciting worlds of HPC, Quantum Computing, & Software Development.



EXPERIENCE

08/2024 - present

Technical Solutions Architect - OXMAINT INC, Silicon Valley, CA

- Led the integration of Artificial Intelligence throughout the product, embedding automation into core workflows, slashing manual effort by 40%, and elevating user engagement metrics by 3x.
- Crafted Al-Agents enhancing 6+ core CMMS modules handling enterprise-grade industry operations, for predictive analytics, performance optimizations, and genAl while prioritizing security and scalability.

11/2022 - 05/2024

(1 yr, 7 mos)

Graduate Research Assistantship - SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY, San Francisco, CA

- Formulated feasibility studies on performing scalable FFT computations 'in situ' on HPC platforms leveraging CPU, GPU & Quantum hardware to support scientific analysis workloads in exascale NERSC projects like WarpX.
- Devised a novel FFT numerical library in C++ for distributed-memory massively parallel processing architecture. Collaborated with scientists at the LBNL supercomputing facility to conduct extended research, achieving a minimum of 10x speedup in computation time compared to traditional methods.

05/2023 - 08/2023

SDE Intern - AMAZON WEB SERVICES (AWS), Seattle, WA

(3 mos)

- Prototyped a robust monitoring service to ensure timely capturing of critical metrics to enhance service reliability by at least 10% after full-fledged deployment on thousands of live AWS servers worldwide as a part of the AWS CloudFront CDN services' platform team.
- Curated live dashboards to provide real-time visibility into at least 70% of all the agents running on servers, empowering the team to actively maintain reliability and diagnose potential issues.

08/2020 - 07/2022

Software Engineer - ELASTICRUN, Pune, IN

(2 yrs)

- Engineered an enterprise-grade ERP platform on the Frappe framework, streamlining logistics and B2B eCommerce processes, while single-handedly contributing to 20% of the 'Velocity' segment's development workload.
- Refined ground-level operational efficiency by executing heavy Python-based server-side development, and PWAs using Flutter and SvelteJS as a full-stack developer in an agile software development environment.
- Orchestrated an automated testing framework and handled bi-weekly live software deployments with the DevOps team based on Kubernetes and GitLab-based CI/CD pipelines, boosting deployment rate and reliability by ≈15%.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

Languages Frameworks Tools Python, C/C++, Java, CUDA, TypeScript, Javascript, SQL, Ruby, R, Go, HTML/CSS, bash.

SENSEI, Oiskit, cuOuantum, Frappe, Diango, Flask, SvelteJS, React, Node.is, MySOL, NoSOL, Redis, Helm. Git, Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras, SciPy/NumPy, MPI/OpenMP, Linux, AWS, GCP, Azure, Docker/Kubernetes,

ElasticSearch, nginx, REST, Linux, PowerBI, Jira.

EDUCATION

MS - COMPUTER SCIENCE, San Francisco State University

High-Performance Computing, Quantum Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Advanced Algorithms

BE - COMPUTER ENGINEERING, International Institute of Information Technology (SPPU) Machine Learning, Data Mining and Analytics, NLP, Cloud Computing, Databases, Data Structures

NOTABLE EXPERIENCES AND PUBLICATIONS

- An integral member of the Early-Career Conference Review Board for the ISAV workshop at The Super-Computing conference (SC23), tasked with a technical assessment of submitted research papers and noteworthy lightning talk on Scalable FFT project research. Peer Reviewed Abstract from the conference: https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01843
- Open Source Contributor to SENSEI Project as a new FFT analysis backed endpoint. %
- Pioneered research on quantifying and benchmarking Quantum Encoding models to identify challenges and computational overheads to optimize the Hybrid Classical-Quantum interface advancing the field of practical quantum computing. HiPC-IEEE awaiting publication % | Extended Thesis % | GitHub % | IBM Quantum Challenge '24 Achievement %
- Architected a GIS project to perform analysis on multi-spectral & temporal satellite data employing Deep Learning Networks & signalmatching algorithms yielding over 80% accuracy and collaborated with scientists from ISRO, NRSC & Geospatial Design Labs. %